<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FreeCon.ga</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/</link><description>Recent content on FreeCon.ga</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:06:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freeconga.github.io/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Empower Your Conga Voice</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/empower-your-conga-voice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 16:06:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/empower-your-conga-voice/</guid><description>Goal Conga 4090 is able to talk instead of just beep to us, so here it is a guide to get it
Requirements A rooted conga At writing time, we just test in 4090 conga model, in other model some people already experimented some trouble. Please, do it just if you know what are you doing.
Steps It is a good practice to do a back up if all the files we are going to handle, so:</description></item><item><title>Clean Me</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/clean-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 19:16:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/clean-me/</guid><description>Goal Get your vacuum close to your bin once the tank is full
Requirements Valetudo integrated into Home assistant Tank percentage sensor available (i.e. with this tuto) A defined spot in valetudo Steps Once the tank percentage sensor is available, this automation is easy just taking care about the actions you may need. We are going to trigger this action every time the vacuum is in the dock for more than 1h, but it will trigger just in case of the tank percentage sensor above of 100.</description></item><item><title>Time and Tank Virtual Sensors</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/time-and-tank-virtual-sensors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 18:57:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/time-and-tank-virtual-sensors/</guid><description>Goal Valetudo is so great, but its home assistant integration miss out some good sensors like the time, area and tank fill percentage.
With this guide, you are going to learn how to create virtual sensor to get the cleaning time and tank percentage based on this time.
Requirements Valetudo integrated into Home assistant Steps Create one input date time helper. In this example the helper will be called RobotStartCleaningTime, being an date and time helper, so the id of this helper will be: input_datetime.</description></item><item><title>Hey Google Clean My Room</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/hey-google-clean-my-room/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:29:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/blog/hey-google-clean-my-room/</guid><description>Goal Say &amp;ldquo;Hey Google, clean my room&amp;rdquo; to trigger your conga to clean that room
Requirements Valetudo integrated into Home assistant Defined zones in Valetudo (or segments) Google assistant integrated in home assistant Vacuum domain exposed from home assistant to Google assistant Steps Once you already know your zone IDs (under info button in zone section from Valetudo), yoy may have to create a script in home assistant to trigger that action in valetudo.</description></item><item><title>About us</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/page/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/page/about/</guid><description>A group o people interested in technology, privacy and -obviously- vacuum cleanning robots 😁
Goals Get rid of &amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo; Stop things (=companies) spying on us and our lives Contribute to the common good</description></item><item><title>Robot Vacuum cleaners by Cecotec</title><link>https://freeconga.github.io/web/page/congas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freeconga.github.io/web/page/congas/</guid><description> Conga 5490 Conga 5090 Conga 4490 Conga 4090 Conga 3790 Conga 3690 Absolute Conga 3590 Conga 3490 Elite Conga 3390 Conga 3290 Titanium Conga Serie 3090 Conga 2690 Conga 2290 Panoramic Conga 2090 Vision Conga 1890 Conga 1690 Pro Conga 1590 Active Conga 1490 Impulse Conga Serie 1390 Conga Serie 1290 Conga Serie 1190 Conga Serie 1099 Connected Conga Serie 1090 Connected Conga Serie 1090 Conga Serie 990 Conga Serie 950 Conga Serie 750</description></item></channel></rss>